Preston Culbertson

Curriculum Vitae

Email: pculbert@caltech.edu

Website: https://www.its.caltech.edu/~pculbert

Education

Stanford University PhD in Mechanical Engineering Advisor: Mac Schwager	2022
Stanford University MS in Mechanical Engineering	2020
Georgia Institute of Technology BS in Mechanical Engineering	2016

Work Experience	
California Institute of Technology Postdoctoral Scholar Advisor: Aaron Ames	2022 - present
Caltech / NASA Jet Propulsion Laboratory NSTRF Visiting Technologist	2018 - 2021
Caltech / NASA Jet Propulsion Laboratory Graduate Student Intern	2017

Research Summary

I am interested in building **collaborative** robots that can **understand and interact** with their environment, humans, and other robots. My primary research interests are **adaptive** and **learning-based control**, **manipulation and grasping**, and **multi-agent interaction and coordination** (especially without communication). My existing research threads are best summarized as:

- Decentralized, adaptive control for collaborative manipulation of unknown objects,
- Integrating learning-based perception methods into robot motion planning, and
- Fast, efficient discrete optimization for assembly, grasp, and motion planning.

Awards

RSS Pioneer, Workshop for top early-career robotics researchers. *Robotics: Science and Systems Pioneers Workshop*, 2021.

ICRA Best Manipulation Paper Award, "Decentralized adaptive control for collaborative manipulation." *ICRA 2018*.

ICRA Best Multi-Robot Systems Paper Finalist, "Decentralized adaptive control for collaborative manipulation." *ICRA 2018*.

NASA Space Technology Research Fellowship, Awarded to 56 students in the US. *National Aeronautics and Space Administration*, 2018.

NSF GRFP Honorable Mention, National Science Foundation Graudate Research Fellowship Program, 2018.

Graduate School of Engineering Fellowship, Stanford University, 2016.

Richard K. Whitehead Jr. Memorial Award, Awarded to the top three graduating seniors in Mechanical Engineering. *Georgia Institute of Technology*, 2016.

President's Scholarship, "Full ride" merit scholarship awarded to top 50 incoming undergraduates, *Georgia Institute of Technology*, 2012.

Teaching Experience

Graduate Teaching Assistant AA273: State Estimation and Filtering for Aerospace Systems	Spring 2022
Graduate Teaching Assistant AA273: State Estimation and Filtering for Aerospace Systems	Spring 2021
Graduate Teaching Assistant AA273: State Estimation and Filtering for Aerospace Systems	Spring 2018
Graduate Teaching Assistant AA277: Multi-Robot Control, Communication, and Sensing	Winter 2018

Academic Publications and Presentations

Iournal Articles

1. T. Chen, **P. Culbertson**, and M. Schwager, "CATNIPS: Collision avoidance through neural implicit probabilistic scenes," in *IEEE Transactions on Robotics (T-RO)*, 2023. *Under Review*.

^{*} indicates equal contribution

- 2. M. Adamkiewicz*, T. Chen*, A. Caccavale, R. Gardner, **P. Culbertson**, J. Bohg, and M. Schwager, "Vision-only robot navigation in a neural radiance world," in *IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters (RA-L)*, 2021.
- 3. A. Cauligi, **P. Culbertson**, E. Schmerling, M. Schwager, B. Stellato, M. Pavone, "CoCo: Online mixed-integer control via supervised learning," in *IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters (RA-L)*, 2021.
- 4. **P. Culbertson**, J.-J. Slotine, M. Schwager, "Decentralized adaptive control for collaborative manipulation of rigid bodies," in *IEEE Transactions on Robotics (T-RO)*, 2021.

Conference Papers

- 1. A. H. Li, **P. Culbertson**, J. W. Burdick, and A. D. Ames, "FRoGGeR: Fast robust grasp generation via the min-weight metric," in *IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems*, 2023. *Under Review*.
- 2. R. K. Cosner, **P. Culbertson**, A. J. Taylor, and A. D. Ames, "Robust safety under stochastic uncertainty with discrete-time control barrier functions," in *Robotics: Science and Systems (RSS)*, 2023. *Under Review*.
- 3. **P. Culbertson**, S. Bandyopadhyay, A. Goel, P. McGarey, and M. Schwager, "Multirobot assembly scheduling for the Lunar Crater Radio Telescope on the far-side of the moon," in *IEEE Aerospace Conference*, 2022.
- 4. C. Chen, **P. Culbertson**, M. Lepert, M. Schwager, and J. Bohg, "TrajectoTree: Trajectory optimization meets tree search for planning multi-contact dexterous manipulation," in *IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)*, 2021.
- 5. A. Cauligi*, **P. Culbertson***, B. Stellato, D. Bertsimas, M. Schwager, and M. Pavone, "Learning mixed-integer convex optimization strategies for robot planning and control," in *Conference on Decision and Control (CDC)*, 2020.
- 6. **P. Culbertson**, S. Bandyopadhyay, and M. Schwager, "Multi-robot assembly sequencing via discrete optimization," in *IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)*, 2019.
- 7. **P. Culbertson** and M. Schwager, "Decentralized adaptive control for collaborative manipulation," in *IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)*, 2018. **Best Manipulation Paper Award.**
- 8. P. Slade, **P. Culbertson**, Z. Sunberg, M. Kochenderfer, "Simultaneous active parameter estimation and control using sampling-based Bayesian reinforcement learning," in *IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robotics and Systems (IROS)*, 2017.

Workshops and Invited Presentations

1. Stanford Machine Learning and Statistics Lunch (Seminar), *Collaborative Manipulation in the Wild*, 2022.

- 2. Ames-Burdick Group Meeting, Caltech (Seminar), Collaborative Manipulation in the Wild, 2021.
- 3. ASE 389: Modeling Multi-Agent Systems, UT Austin (Guest Lecture), *Decentralized Adaptive Control for Collaborative Manipulation*, 2021.
- 4. NASA Technology Integration Meeting on Lunar Excavation and Construction, *Collaborative Manipulation for Space Exploration and Construction*, 2021.
- 5. Learning Meets Combinatorial Algorithms Workshop, Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), CoCo: Learning Mixed-Integer Convex Optimization Strategies for Robot Planning and Control, 2020.
- 6. Bay Area Machine Learning Symposium, Learning Mixed-Integer Convex Optimization Strategies for Robot Planning and Control, 2020.
- 7. AA277: Multi-Robot Control, Communication and Sensing (Guest Lecture), *Decentralized Adaptive Control for Collaborative Manipulation*, 2019.
- 8. Conference on Learning for Dynamics and Control (L4DC), *Decentralized Adaptive Control of Hamiltonian Systems*, 2019.
- 9. Bay Area Robotics Symposium (BARS), Decentralized Adaptive Control for Collaborative Manipulation, 2017.

Professional Activities

Professional Service

- 1. Co-organizer, Workshop on Motion Planning with Implicit Neural Representations of Geometry, International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), 2022.
- 2. Faculty Committee, RSS Pioneers Workshop, Robotics: Science and Systems, 2022.
- 3. Program Committee, Robot Learning Workshop: Self-Supervised and Lifelong Learning, Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2021.

Review Activities

- 1. American Control Conference
- 2. IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)
- 3. IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)
- 4. IEEE International Conference on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics (SMC)
- 5. Field Robotics
- 6. IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters (R-AL)

- 7. IEEE Robotics and Autonomous Systems
- 8. IEEE Transactions on Artificial Intelligence (T-AI)
- 9. IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control (T-AC)
- 10. IEEE Transactions on Robotics (T-RO)

Mentorship Activities

- 1. Graduate Research Mentor, Multi-Robot Systems Lab, 2018-2022.
- 2. After-School Tutor, S.A.Y. Yes! Center, 2015-2016.
- 3. Programming Workshop Leader, Vine City Code Crew, 2015-2016.